Over a century ago, beings that
prey on humans suddenly appeared.
Their absolutely overwhelming strength
quickly pushed humanity to
the brink of extinction.
The surviving humans constructed
three walls: Maria, Rose, and Sina,
which brought them a century of peace.
However...
Unknown are the names
of the flowers that have been trampled
Birds have fallen to the earth
and long for the wind
Prayers won't solve anything
Only the will to fight
can change the here and now!
O pigs who laugh at the resolve
to walk over corpses to move forward
Livestock complacency? False prosperity?
Give us the freedom of dying,
starving wolves!
The humiliation of being caged
is what triggers us to fight back
We hunters slaughter prey
beyond the castle walls,
consumed with surging bloodlust,
as our crimson bows and arrows
pierce scarlet holes into the twilight
"That Day"
"The Fall of Shiganshina, Part 2"
Till that time I had been a wretched soul,
and wholly giv'n to greed!
Now, as thou see'st,
I'm punished for it here!
What avarice doth
is here made manifest,
in this purgation of converted souls!
Nor hath this Mount a penalty more bitter!
Stop!
Let me go!
O Avarice!
Thou hast to thyself so drawn my race,
that ev'n for its own flesh it careth not!
What more canst thou do with us?!
O Avarice! Thou hast to thyself--
Eren! What are you doing?!
We were so close to saving Mom!
Why couldn't you mind your own business?!
--We were so close to saving her!
--Knock it off, dammit!
Eren!
Eren.
You couldn't save your mother
because you lacked the strength.
And I...
I couldn't stand up to the Titan...
...because I lacked the courage!
I'm sorry.
It's happened again...
Hurry! To the inner gate!
Escape aboard the boats there!
Hurry! Before you get eaten!
City districts like Shiganshina that
stick out in vital spots along the wall
serve to attract the Titans and streamline
security costs and troop numbers.
Performing true to its role as a Titan target,
Shiganshina had but one inner gate
through which its citizens could flee.
Discard your belongings!
Let as many people on as possible!
Sit, Armin.
But Eren and Mikasa still aren't here.
There they are!
Eren?
Just let him be for now.
The poor thing.
How very traumatized he must be...
Huh?
What are you dawdling for?!
Hurry the hell up!
Get those cannons loaded!
Hurry!
They're closing in!
This can't be for real...!
Please, God...
Please, God... Please, God...
Hey!
Hey! What are you doing?!
It's at full capacity! It has to leave!
No! Please! At least let our children on!
I'm sorry, but we can't!
Get going!
--Let us on!
You idiot! What are you aiming at?!
B-But, Sir, these aren't
accurate enough to aim with!
I don't give a crap!
Get 'em reloaded at once!
It's no use!
The gate's closing...!
Retreat! We're gonna get left behind!
Hey!
Don't shut it! Hold on a little longer!
There are still lots of people in there!
If the Titans get through,
the town being overrun
will be the least of our worries!
All of humankind will be forced
to withdraw behind the next wall!
But that's no reason to
leave these people to die!
Shut it! Hurry!
The Titans are coming!
Close the gate at once!
Stop!
Hey!
What the...?
It's...!
Fire!
--What?!
--No effect?!
It's...!
It's coming! Retreat!
A Titan's coming! It's charging this way!
Hurry! Shut the gate!
The gate...
Within hours of the fall of Shiganshina
on the south side of Wall Maria,
news of the incident had reached
every city inside human territory.
Is it true the Titans
"South side of Wall Rose" "Trost District"
have overrun Shiganshina?!
I can't believe this!
The walls have held strong
for a century! Why now?!
Whether we believe it or not,
the fact is that refugees have
fled here by boat!
Reports say there are five hundred on board.
The question is if Shiganshina
is all that was affected...
But, surely they couldn't have
gotten through Wall Maria as well?
In any event,
we must contact the central
government and request instructions.
This crisis is far too much
for us to handle on our own.
I'm sorry to interrupt!
A courier horse has just arrived!
Titans have breached
Wall Maria and entered its interior!
It's over...
It's all over...
The Titans are going
to devour humanity again...
This is the end...?
I'll... never see
that house... ever again...
Why...?!
Why'd I argue for no reason like that?!
Why was that all I could do?!
And now Mom's gone!
She's never coming back!
Why...?!
Because you lacked the strength.
It's because I'm weak...
Because humans are weak...
Is crying the only
thing the weak can do?!
I'm... going to...
Eren.
What's gotten into you, Eren?
Eren...
...drive them out!
I'm going to drive out...
...every last one from this world!
Eren...
The same year, the central
government made the decision
to withdraw all of humanity's
domain behind Wall Rose.
An estimated 10,000 people
were eaten by Titans during this time.
Eren...
Carla...
Mikasa...
Please be all right!
Eren!
Dad!
Stop, Dad!
What are you trying to do?!
Just give me your arm!
No!
Mom's death has made you go crazy!
Eren!
Let go, Dad!
It's for...
...your own sake!
What are you talking about?!
Listen! Don't forget the key!
You must reach it!
Until... you learn...
the truth someday...!
Eren, are you okay?
You were having a nightmare.
I feel like I just saw Dad...
No, you were dreaming.
Oh...
Let's go.
They said they're going to hand out food.
Apparently this was their food storehouse.
They've gathered all the boat refugees here.
--Hey! Get in line, will ya?!
--Shut up!
I ain't eaten anything since last night!
We can't say we've survived just yet.
Eren!
Mikasa!
Armin...
Here! Just in time!
My grandpa got us some
by saying it was for children!
Thank you.
What's his problem?
You can't blame him.
There's probably not
enough food to go around.
And that's an entire day's worth.
There are just too many refugees.
There was already
a food shortage going on,
plus the people here aren't treated
as well as citizens on the outer wall.
--This is mine!
--Shut up!
Why should we hafta give our
food to some lousy outsiders?
If the Titans got through the wall,
they could've at least eaten
some more people, if you ask me!
Eren!
This is just gonna make
the food shortage even worse.
Oww!
What the hell?! You damn kid!
You don't know what it's like!
You've never even seen it!
You've never seen
what the Titans do to people!
Shut up!
I apologize!
He's just hungry and irritable!
That's why he so rudely
lashed out at an adult...
I'm very sorry!
Man...
It's 'cause of us that you guys
aren't starving to death, you know!
Even you kids oughta be thankful to us!
Of course!
Damn...
I refuse to let them take care of me.
I'm going back--to Wall Maria!
I'm going to destroy every last Titan!
Eren...
You're not being serious, are you?
I'm serious!
I'm not like those guys who do
nothing but act tough inside the walls!
I don't need this crap!
Eren! You'll starve to death!
Doesn't it bother you at all?!
It's because we take everyone's
charity that we can't beat the Titans!
It's impossible!
There is no beating them!
All we can do is live inside the walls!
If we try anything, we'll die!
Just like my mom and dad!
So you're just gonna grovel to them then?!
That's not shameful to you?!
There's... There's nothing
we can do for now!
That's just an excuse!
If you wanna live like
livestock forever, go ahead!
You wimp!
Mikasa...
If Armin's a wimp, then so are we.
Whether it was running
from the Titans or fleeing the town,
we didn't manage anything on our own.
We even had help finding food today.
There's no way such powerless people
can defeat even a
single one of those Titans.
Staying alive is what matters most.
Just like your mother said.
Mikasa!
You have to eat and stay alive.
I won't let you starve to death.
Several days later,
the throngs of refugees
were tasked with cultivating
the wastelands to secure food.
However, a food shortage was unavoidable.
So, in the following year of 846,
the central government sent a
multitude of refugees on a mission
in the name of retaking Wall Maria.
Of the 250,000 sent--
nearly 20% of the population--
not even 200 survived.
Although it wasn't much,
their sacrifices did improve
the food shortage situation
for the rest of the population.
It's all the Titans' fault.
If we could just subdue them,
our place in the world could be ours again.
Armin.
I'm going to apply for the Cadets next year.
I'm going to gain the
strength to fight the Titans!
Me too...
Armin?!
Me too!
I will, too.
Mikasa...!
You don't need to! You said yourself
staying alive is what's important!
Yes. That's why I'm doing it;
so you won't die.
All right. The three of us, then.
The 104th Cadet Corps Class
entrance ceremony will now begin!
You have the misfortune of having me,
Keith Sadies, as your commandant!
I do not welcome you warmly!
In your current state, you'd
be nothing but food for the Titans!
You're mere livestock!
You're less than livestock!
Over the next three years,
we're going to train you worthless nothings
and teach you how to fight Titans!
Three years from now, when you
come face-to-face with the Titans,
will you still be fodder for them?!
Will you serve as an honorable
barrier that protects the king?!
Or will you be a glorious soldier
for humanity that drives the Titans out!
It's up to you to decide!
Yes. I'll be one.
I'll drive out every last Titan!
Your dreams are where your heart is
They're more fragile than life itself
Over and over you cast them aside,
only to find more
Now, rest in peace
Pounding impulses defile the things we wish for
and the more we forget
the more we remember again
In this beautiful, cruel world
all I can do is ask why we're still alive
Oh, with our strength--and our weakness--
what are we going to protect if there's no sense
to anything anymore?
He fails as a soldier.
Eren joins the Cadets,
vowing revenge against the Titans,
but his failure at basic training
comes as a harsh reality.
"A Dim Light Amid Despair"
"Humanity's Comeback, Part 1"